# **Sandy Goreraza**

Full Stack Web Developer



#### **SUMMARY**

An experienced, capable and agile IT Professional with a demonstrated history of focus and accomplishment in formulating Systems development and administration solutions for large corporates. Through a balance of academia and "hands on" working experience, I have attained rare and transferable technical competencies that include a highly developed goal orientation, effective team leadership and efficient task prioritisation. I believe that this mix of skills would add significant value to any employing organisation. My value proposition for prospective employers is surmised as a transfer of technical and academic prowess, single minded focus and conceptual / practical agility in exchange for the acquisition of a higher level of professional learning, growth and development.

#### **EDUCATION & COURSES**



# Certified Full Stack Web Developer - Flask Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 Python

pirple.com

Online Training Course

Learned 4 key areas of full stack development: Frontend, Backend, Database design, and Hosting. Using Python3, Flask, Twitter Bootstrap and SQLite to build a fully-functional web application, then deploy it to a virtual server on Digital Ocean.

#### The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Google Digital Garage

Online Training Course

Mastered the basics of digital marketing. The course is accredited by Interactive Advertising Bureau Europe and The Open University. Learned 26 modules , all created by Google trainers, packed with full of practical exercises and real-world examples to helping gaining knowledge into action.

# Unix/Linux and Shell Scripting - Crash Course Apr 2021 - Apr 2021

Alison

Online Training Course

Learned about file permissions, introduction to Linux Commands and using tools like Git, Python, shell script and Grep.

# Google Africa Developer Training Program Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

Google Developers

- Online Training Course
- Undertook an extensive 6 months training in Android design and development offered through the Google Africa Developer Scholarship program.

# ISO / IEC 27001 - Information Security Associate

Jan **2021** - Feb **2021** 

skillFront.com

- Online Training Course
- Learned the fundamentals of ISO/IEC 27001 in Information Security systems.

#### Certified Network Security Specialist CNSS

Mar 2020 - May 2020

ICSI (International CyberSecurity Institute), UK

- Online Training Course
- This course provides a holistic view of modern network security including operating system hardening, firewalls, intrusion-detection

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Ħ,

#### Full Stack Web Developer

Mar 2014 - Present -

Zimbabwe Tourism Authority

- Zimbabwe
- Designed and Developed a virtual exhibition platform with video chat that is used by both domestic and international market. The platforms saves the company more than 40 000 USD annually.
- Designed and developed a robust e-registration platform for the Tourism industry. The platform was built before the deadline.
- Developed WhatsApp chat bots APIs to promote marketing efforts by the Authority.
- Provide adequate training to staff and the tourism industry on how to use developed platforms.
- Devised various custom responsive WordPress sites from design comps that includes advanced WordPress features, such as Custom Post Types, Advanced Custom Fields and WordPress Customize API.
- Proactively liaised with department personnel and project manager to ensure efficient and timely delivery of significant projects.

#### Freelancer Web Developer

Feb 2019 - Apr 2020

Place of Stone

- Harare, Zimbabwe
- Undertook a project that led to the design, development and launch of an online travel booking portal for the Company.

#### Lead Backend Developer

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

**CST Advisory Services** 

- Harare, Zimbabwe
- Led a team of IT Professionals in the role of Senior Web Developer on a crowd funding portal.

# PHP 80% Communication 70% Self-motivation 80% Decision Making 90%

systems, VPNs and Encryption. Physical Security, Standards, System Security and Security Policies are also included.

Programmed Languages in PHP, Python, C#, Aug 2018 - Nov 2018 Algorithms and Data Structures, WordPress and Systems Security

teamtreehouse.com

Online Training Course

Bachelor of Business Studies and Computing Feb 2010 - Oct 2013 Science Degree

University of Zimbabwe

Harare, Zimbabwe

#### **LANGUAGES**

囯

English Shona  $\odot$   $\odot$   $\odot$   $\odot$ 

 $\odot$   $\odot$   $\odot$   $\odot$ 

## MOST PROUD OF





Creative Thinking, Effectiveness, Productivity



Analyzing Issues, Decision Making, Project Management, Strategic Planning

**101** Team Work

Collaboration, Delegation, Goal Setting, Group Leadership

# AREAS OF EXPERTISE



Ex. Marketing Brands

Ex. Marketing Brands

Web Development

SEO

WhatsApp Chat Bot

Digital Marketing

Systems Design

## **HOBBIES**





Travel



Games



Reading

Maptability Didhan	90%
Python	70%
Laravel	60%
Flask	60%
Codelgnitor	70%
Vue.js	70%
Android Kotlin	70%
Systems Security	90%
WordPress	90%
Microsoft Apps	100%
WhatsApp Chatbot API	100%

## **ONLINE RESUME**



#### Official Resume

Phttps://sandygoreraza.github.io/VueResume/

#### **MY TIME**



